Jason Woodson

jwoodson2014@gmail.com | (804)-921-2290 | linkedin.com/in/jcwoodson | github.com/jwoodson2014

SUMMARY

Dedicated and passionate individual with 3 years of professional experience in consulting and a strong background in data analysis. Currently pursuing a Master's in Business Analytics at the University of Iowa and looking to transition into role in data analytics, specifically within the sports analytics space.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Master of Science, Business Analytics, University of Iowa

December 2022

Certified Public Accountant in the State of Virginia

November 2019

Bachelor of Science, Accounting and Information Systems, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

May 2018

Bachelor of Science, Finance, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

May 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, R, SQL, Basic VBA Programming and User Interface Development

Visualization: Tableau

Data Analysis: Advanced Microsoft Excel, Alteryx, JMP, Orange, Hadoop

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Iowa – Iowa City, Iowa

Graduate Teaching Assistant – ACCT 3450 & 3451

August 2021 - May 2022

- Assisted in teaching two sessions of weekly classes during the fall semester
- Held office hours sessions twice a week, including over winter break (Professor gave students the option to complete class over break)
- Will be leading the review of over 800 tax returns prepared by students for low income residents in the Iowa City area

Grader – BAIS 3250

August 2021 – December 2021

- Dedicated between 2-10 hours a week grading lab exercises, homework assignments, and exams for 120 students
- All grading was done using R programming language

KPMG LLP - Washington, D.C.

Securitization Tax Senior Associate

October 2020 – August 2021

- Advise clients on strategies for the taxable consequences of collateralized loan obligations and other fixed income securities, including risk retention strategies related to the Dodd-Frank Act and the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act
- Assisted in the development of KPMG's first internal, cloud-based processing system used to analyze cash flows of fixed income securities to advise clients more accurately on tax planning matters over the life of collateralized loan obligations
- Oversaw the work of five first and second year associates while assuring client deliverables were sent within the deadline
- Responsible for maintaining project budgets to meet strict profit margin goals set by directors and partners

Securitization Tax Associate

October 2018 – October 2020

- Analyze complex cash flows and transactions, sometimes in excess of 10,000, for the tax planning and reporting for collateralized loan obligation (CLO) issuers, including clients with AUM in excess of \$10 billion
- Developed expertise in federal and international income tax matters
- Clients include five of the top twenty CLO managers in the United States

LEADERSHIP

Mentor, Higher Achievement

September 2019 – May 2021

- Volunteered as a mentor for 5th and 6th graders in Washington, D.C. public schools
- Conducted sessions once a week centered around current events to help students learn about topics directly affecting students

Elected Member, Chesapeake Advisory Staff Counsel, KMPG LLP

August 2019 - August 2021

- Served as head of the "Lunch and Learn" Committee and planned informational events for staff across the Chesapeake region
- Organized information session for first-time home buyers and resources on how to better your mental health in the workplace